

□ 087 7769791 | Marilian killian bis@gmail.com | Marilian killian connor.info | Marilian killian connor | Marilian killian killian connor | Marilian killian kill

Summary _____

Software Developer with a strong desire to show capabilities in a new role. Over the last 12 months I have undertaken courses to build a strong skillset in Web Development technologies and build a portfolio to demonstrate these skills - all Source Code and Live Previews of web apps I've created are accessible from my Github Profile and Portfolio Website linked below.

Experienced IT professional with 6 years experience across a range of roles in the IT sector, including 3 years as a Lead Business Analyst working closely with an offshore development team in an Agile Environment to deliver new IT software and implement change requests on existing systems to better serve End Users and Customers. Hold an MBS and BSc in Business Information Systems from University College Cork.

Now looking to develop strong professional software development experience. Genuine personal enjoyment from learning new technologies and tools, with a passion for problem-solving challenging tasks.

Skills_

Front-end ReactJS, HTML, CSS (including Tailwind), Bootstrap, Webpack

Back-end SQL, REST API

Programming JavaScript, Python, VBA

GitHub https://github.com/killian-oconnor

Portfolio Website http://killianoconnor.info/

Professional Experience Highlights _____

Navi Group Dublin, Ireland

BUSINESS SUPPORT

Sep. 2017 - Dec. 2020

- · Held dual responsibility in the IT function of CarePlus and Staywell Pharmacy brands in both Business Analyst and IT support functions
- · Reporting directly to the CIO, gained valuable experience in numerous areas in a rapidly growing company
- · Working in an agile environment, providing expertise as needed for new projects and acquisitions, while being the primary IT support resource for over 70 Pharmacies throughout the Republic of Ireland

Business Analysis Web Design

- Documenting and prioritising development change requests to Touchplus ordering platform and Retail Solutions POS systems used in stores
- SQL maintenance of product file and integration with SAP HANA system

Axel Ordering Platform - Business Analyst / Test Manager

- Delivered wireframe prototypes and liaised with offshore development team from conception to release to ensure product was business ready and fit for purpose on launch
- Created and maintained requirements documentation
- · Created test cases for testing phase of product development, oversaw testing process with internal users and provided approval for completion
- · The Axel platform is now in use across over 150 pharmacies in the Republic of Ireland, being used daily by customers to keep stock in store replenished and reduce both workload on shop floor staff and cost of products being sold in store for increased margins

IT Support

- Successfully closed over 2000 support cases through technical and functional analysis
- Provided heightened post go live support for new systems and pharmacies
- Regularly assigned to provide a direct point of contact and escalation for any frustrated pharmacy staff and owners
- Oversaw the direct installations of IT systems and training for 40 pharmacies to deploy 3 integrated software systems automating a large portion of traditionally manual tasks such as stock replenishment and management
- · Implemented training plans with Pharmacy staff and Owners on efficient ordering system use and sales reporting capability, taking end users working in stores from having never used our software or another online stock replenishment platform to being fully operational over the course of 3 days

ESB IT Services Dublin, Ireland

GRADUATE PROGRAMME | BUSINESS ANALYST & PROJECT OFFICE & PRODUCT SUPPORT

Sep. 2014 - Sep. 2017

- Creation of lessons learned database utilising VBA. This was a searchable repository for lessons learned recorded in projects across the organisation
- Implemented an automated extraction, reformatting and insertion of data from OpenPursuit CRM application to a PowerBI dashboard using VBA. This work transformed a task assigned for a full day's work per week to an automated process taking seconds, with the generated report dashboard being provided to upper management to monitor overall support cases and incidents
- · Implementation of VBA macros to automate reformatting of SAP data extracts into appropriate excel structure
- Test manager role on Exchange Upgrade project. Created test cases and oversaw testing across 40 users. Project passed testing phase on time and was successfully deployed across the organisation with 700 users being upgraded

Education

The Odin Project

Online Web Development Curriculum

2021 - Current

- · An open-source web-based curriculum to develop the requisite skills for a career in Web Development
- Skills developed include: Javascript programming principles, ReactJS, CSS, Git Version Control, Responsive Web Design

University College Cork

Cork, Ireland

BUSINESS INFORMATION SYSTEMS - MBS 2:1

Sep 2013 - Jun. 2014

• Final Year Project: Worked as part of a 5 person group in association with Gestational Diabetes team in Cork University Hospital to develop a Website and Android application to allow diabetic patients to record a diary of blood glucose readings, which were then stored on a cloud server and shared with medical professionals, as well as visualised in graphs. My primary role was the solo development of the Android application which had CRUD functionality with our online MySQL database

University College Cork

Cork, Ireland

BUSINESS INFORMATION SYSTEMS - BSc (Hons)

Sep 2009 - Jun. 2013

Modules studied include; Web Development, Android Development, Interaction Design, Object Oriented Programming, Database Design, System Analysis and Design

Christian Brothers College Cork

Cork, Ireland

LEAVING CERTIFICATE

Sep 2003 - Jun. 2009

· 420 Leaving Certificate Points

Additional Qualifications, Certifications and Interests _____

- Certified Completion of Harvard CS50x Introduction to Computer Science
- Completion of **ESB Project Management Framework** Training based on Prince II
- BCS Certificate in Requirements Engineering from SQS
- Achieved Distinction in Grade 8 Communication Skills with Trinity Guildhall
- Enjoy Weightlifting, Running and Golf Member of Fota Island Golf Club